export const CHEMISTRYA2019 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. The periodic table is an arrangement of elements according to their?",
A: "Oxidation number",
B: "Atomic number",
C: "Mass number",
D: "Number of neutrons",
answer: "B. Atomic number",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. A solid with higher melting and boiling points is likely to be?",
A: "Covalent compound",
B: "A Dative compound",
C: "An Electrovalent compound",
D: "A Non-metal",
answer: "C. An Electrovalent compound",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. Which of the following metals reacts slowly with cold water?",
A: "Iron",
B: "Silver",
C: "Calcium",
D: "Potassium",
answer: "C. Calcium",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. which of the following elements has the highest ionization energy?",
A: "Calcium",
B: "Chlorine",
C: "Fluorine",
D: "Magnesium",
answer: "D. Magnesium",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. The bleaching action of chlorine is through the process?",
A: "Hydration",
B: "Hydrolysis",
C: "Reduction",
D: "Oxidation",
answer: "D. Oxidation",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. If 6.5g of magnesium ribbon reacts completely with Hydrochloric acid, how many grams of hydrogen gas would be liberated? Mg(s) + 2 HCl(aq) --> MgCl2(aq) + H2(g) [ H = 1.0, Mg = 24.0 ]",
A: "0.54g",
B: "0.70g",
C: "1.08g",
D: "1.40g",
answer: "A. 0.54g",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. Calcium and magnesium belong to the group of the periodic table because both?",
A: "are metals",
B: "form cations",
C: "form colourless salts",
D: "have same number of valence electrons",
answer: "D. have same number of valence electrons",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. Which of the substances is non-polar?",
A: "Bromine",
B: "Ammonia",
C: "Water",
D: "Hydrogen Bromide",
answer: "A. Bromine",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. Which of the following pairs of components have the same molecular mass? [ H = 1.0, C = 12.0, O = 16.0 ]",
A: "Ethene and Ethyne",
B: "Ethane and Ethene",
C: "Carbon (ii) Oxide and Ethene",
D: "Carbon (iv) Oxide and Ethyne",
answer: "C. Carbon (ii) Oxide and Ethene",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. When an equilibrium is established between dissolved and undissolved solutes, the solution is said to be?",
A: "Saturated",
B: "Unsaturated",
C: "Concentrated",
D: "Diluted",
answer: "A. Saturated",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. How many moles of carbon(iv)oxide contains 16.0g of oxygen? [ C = 12.0, O = 16.0 ]",
A: "0.20 mol",
B: "0.25 mol",
C: "0.40 mol",
D: "0.50 mol",
answer: "D. 0.50 mol",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. Stoichiometry is based on the law?",
A: "multiple proportion",
B: "constant composition",
C: "conservation of energy",
D: "conservation of mass",
answer: "D. conservation of mass",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. What is the percentage by mass of H in CH3COOH? [CH3COOH = 60]",
A: "1.7%",
B: "5.0%",
C: "6.7%",
D: "7.1%",
answer: "C. 6.7%",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. Which of the following compounds has coordinate bonds in its structure?",
A: "Al2Cl6",
B: "MgCl2",
C: "AgCl",
D: "NaCl",
answer: "A. Al2Cl6",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. The name of the compound CH3C(CH3)CH2CH2CH3",
A: "2 - methyl butane",
B: "2,2 - dimethyl butane",
C: "2 - methyl pentane",
D: "2,2 - dimethyl pentane",
answer: "D. 2,2 - dimethyl pentane",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. The properties of a good primary standard include the following except?",
A: "High molecular mass",
B: "low molecular mass",
C: "high degree of purity",
D: "readily available",
answer: "B. low molecular mass",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. What is the solubility of a salt X at 25ºC if the saturated solution of the salt contains 0.28g in 100cm3 of the solution in mol per dm3? [X = 56.0 g]",
A: "0.05",
B: "0.10",
C: "2.60",
D: "2.80",
answer: "A. 0.05",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. Vinegar is an aqueous solution of?",
A: "Hydrochloric acid",
B: "ethanedioc acid",
C: "ethanoic acid",
D: "hydrofluoric acid",
answer: "C. ethanoic acid",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. which of the following solutions containing one mole per dm3 of the compound would have the lowest PH?",
A: "ethanoic acid",
B: "hydrochloric acid",
C: "sodium chloride",
D: "sodium hydrogentrioxocarbonate(iv)",
answer: "B. hydrochloric acid",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. A sample of air was bubbled into water. The PH of the water slowly changed from 7 to 6. Which of the following gases in the samples caused the change?",
A: "carbon(iv)oxide",
B: "carbon(ii)oxide",
C: "nitrogen",
D: "oxygen",
answer: "A. carbon(iv)oxide",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. The most suitable indicator for the reaction between NaOH and HCOOH is?",
A: "bromocresol",
B: "methyl orange",
C: "methyl red",
D: "phenolphthalein",
answer: "D. phenolphthalein",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. consider the following reaction equation: 2Al(OH)3 + 3H2SO4 →Al2(SO4)3(aq)+6H2O. How many moles of tetraoxosulphate(vi)acid is needed to produce 0.5mol of aluminium tetraoxosulphate(vi)?",
A: "0.5",
B: "1.0",
C: "1.5",
D: "3.0",
answer: "C. 1.5",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. which of the following pairs of substances has the highest heat of neutralization?",
A: "strong acid and strong base",
B: "weak acid and weak base",
C: "strong acid and weak base",
D: "weak acid and strong base",
answer: "A. strong acid and strong base",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. When quicklime dissolves in water?",
A: "heat is absorbed",
B: "heat is evolved",
C: "oxygen is liberated",
D: "hydrogen is given off",
answer: "B. heat is evolved",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. If the value of ΔH is positive for a reaction, it means that the reaction is?",
A: "exothermic",
B: "endothermic",
C: "spontaneous",
D: "slow",
answer: "B. endothermic",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. Which of the following compounds is formed by the oxidation of ethanol?",
A: "C2H4CO2H",
B: "C2H5CO2H",
C: "CH3OH",
D: "CH3CO2H",
answer: "D. CH3CO2H",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. What is the name of the gas liberated when diluted hydrochloric acid is added to iron(ii)sulphide?",
A: "turns lime water milky",
B: "decolorizes bromine water",
C: "gives a pop sound",
D: "turns lead(ii)ethanoate paper black",
answer: "D. turns lead(ii)ethanoate paper black",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. An organic compound contains 72% carbon, 12% hydrogen and 16% oxygen by mass. What is the empirical formula of the compound? [ H = 1.0. C = 12.0, O = 16.0 ]",
A: "C3H8O",
B: "C6H12O",
C: "C6H12O2",
D: "C12H12O11",
answer: "B. C6H12O",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. When excess chlorine is mixed with ethane at room temperature, the product formed is?",
A: "1,2-dichloroethane",
B: "1,2-dichloroethene",
C: "1,1-dichloroethane",
D: "1,1-dichloroethene",
answer: "A. 1,2-dichloroethane",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. which of the following reagents could be used to distinguish between propan-1-ol and propan-2-ol",
A: "H+K2Cr2O7",
B: "I2/ OH-",
C: "CH3COOH",
D: "NaCl",
answer: "A. H+K2Cr2O7",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. If a catalyst is added to a system, the temperature and the pressure remain constant, there would be no effect on the?",
A: "activation energy of the reaction",
B: "rate of the reaction",
C: "rate of the reverse reaction",
D: "heat of reaction",
answer: "D. heat of reaction",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. consider the following reaction equation: 2NH3 + 3Cl2 → N2 + 6HCl.  NH3 is acting as?",
A: "a reducing agent",
B: "a dehydrating agent",
C: "a drying agent",
D: "an oxidizing agent",
answer: "A. a reducing agent",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. The oxidation of chromium in Cr2O7−2 ?",
A: "+4",
B: "+5",
C: "+6",
D: "+7",
answer: "C. +6",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. The process by which alkanoic acid reacts reversibly with alkanols is known as?",
A: "saponification",
B: "esterification",
C: "carboxylation",
D: "halogenation",
answer: "B. esterification",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. If the oxidation potential of Mg and Al are +2.37 volts and + 1.66 volts respectively, then the Mg would?",
A: "not replace Al",
B: "be replaced by Al",
C: "remain in the solution",
D: "replace Al",
answer: "B. be replaced by Al",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. consider the reaction represented by the following equation: 2SO2 + O2  ⇌ 2SO3",
A: "decrease in the concentration of SO2",
B: "have no effect on the reaction",
C: "shift the equilibrium position to the left",
D: "shift the equilibrium position to the right",
answer: "D. shift the equilibrium position to the right",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. In a mixture of gases which do not react chemically together, the pressure of the individual gas is?",
A: "atmospheric pressure",
B: "vapor pressure",
C: "total pressure",
D: "partial pressure",
answer: "D. partial pressure",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. Biotechnology is applied in the?",
A: "treatment of sewage",
B: "treatment of water",
C: "purification of chemicals",
D: "purification of metals",
answer: "A. treatment of sewage",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. which of the following organic compounds has the lowest boiling point?",
A: "C6H14",
B: "C5H12",
C: "C4H10",
D: "(CH3)3CH",
answer: "B. C5H12",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. X and Y respectively are?",
A: "ethane and ethene",
B: "ethene and ethane",
C: "ethyne and ethene",
D: "ethane and ethyne",
answer: "B. ethene and ethane",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. Which of the following substances can be classified as heavy chemicals?",
A: "CaOCl2",
B: "H2SO4",
C: "AgNO3",
D: "CaO",
answer: "C. AgNO3",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. in Boyle's law?",
A: "T is constant, P varies directly with V",
B: "P is constant, V varies inversely with T",
C: "V is constant, P varies directly with T",
D: "T is constant, V varies inversely with P",
answer: "D. T is constant, V varies inversely with P",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. Which of the following apparatus is NOT used in volumetric analysis?",
A: "Pipette",
B: "Burette",
C: "Desiccator",
D: "conical flask",
answer: "C. Desiccator",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. One of the deductions from Rutherford's alpha particle scattering experiment is that?",
A: "electrons are negatively charged",
B: "electrons have a negligible mass",
C: "nuclei of atoms are positively charged",
D: "protons are positively charged",
answer: "C. nuclei of atoms are positively charged",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. The atoms have the same number of?",
A: "nucleon",
B: "electrons",
C: "neutrons",
D: "protons",
answer: "C. neutrons",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. The number of electrons in the 3d orbital of 24Cr is",
A: "2",
B: "3",
C: "4",
D: "5",
answer: "D. 5",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. The method used to collect gas in the laboratory depends on its? \nI. boiling point   \nII. density   \nIII. smell   \nIV. solubility in water",
A: "I and II only",
B: "II and IV only",
C: "III and IV",
D: "I, II, III and IV",
answer: "D. i, ii, iii and iv",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question48",
question:  "48. Which of the following methods is NOT used for the separation of mixtures?",
A: "Chromatography",
B: "Crystallization",
C: "Distillation",
D: "Electrolysis",
answer: "D. valence electrons",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question49",
question:  "49. The group to which elements belong in the periodic table is determined by the number?",
A: "electrons",
B: "core electrons",
C: "valence shells",
D: "valence electrons",
answer: "Z. zzzzzzzzzzz",
correctLetter: "Z",
correctOption: 9,
},

{
id: "question50",
question:  "50. Kipps apparatus can be used to prepare?",
A: "H2",
B: "NH3",
C: "O2",
D: "H2S",
answer: "D. H2S",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},


]